Department of History fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Department of History fonds
1964 - 1994
F-26
1.75 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Department of History
The Department of History is one of the original Departments of the Faculty of Arts, and began to offer courses leading to a B.A. when the University opened in 1965. The Department's offerings were expanded with the addition in 1966 of M.A. and Ph.D. programs. The Department was responsible, through its Head, for the promotion of research and the development and delivery of programs in the field of history. An adjunct to this function was its responsibility to develop and provide instruction in programs offered outside the Department, including the Canadian Studies, Graduate Liberal Studies, Humanities Minor, and Women's Studies Programs. The Department also had institutional links with the Department of Spanish and Latin American Studies and the French Department. It also acted as an advisory body for the History Department of Fraser Valley University College.
The Department's activities included participation in university and external associations and committees, the organization of and participation in conferences, and involvement in the publication of International History Review.
The Department was administered by a Chair and standing committees. The Chair was the chief academic and administrative officer, responsible for all administrative, fiscal and academic activities of the Department. The number and composition of Department committees changed greatly over time. The Revised Constitution of 1969 listed seven standing committees: Salary, Tenure and Promotion; Appointments; Grievance; Library; Faculty-Student Liaison; Graduate Studies; and Undergraduate Studies. There were also a number of ad hoc committees, including the Chairman's Search Committee, the Goals and Implementation Committee, and the Nominating Committee.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
The fonds of the Department of History consists of records created and received in the course of the administration of the department and the carrying out of its functions of providing instruction and promoting research. The activities documented include policy and procedures development; the planning, initiation and administration of curriculum and programs; departmental and faculty meetings; faculty salary, appointment, promotion and tenure deliberations; departmental reviews; and the publication of journals and reports. The types of documents include meeting agenda, correspondence, course outlines and examinations, an external review, faculty files, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and reports.
The titles and arrangement of series were provided by the archivist.
Cole, Doug; Auty, Phyllis; Johnston, Hugh; Mugridge, Ian; Hutchinson, John; Koepke, Robert; Kup, A. P.; Cunningham, Allan B.
The records were transferred in a number of accessions from the Department, beginning in the early 1980s.
Additional material has been accessioned but not yet processed (as of September 2002: 2 m., 1989-1992). Please consult the archivist for information about using these materials; restrictions may apply. Further accruals are expected.
Consult the inventory of the Faculty of Arts fonds, F-2.
Some access restrictions may apply in accordance with Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy legislation. Consult the appropriate series level description and the archivist.
File lists are available.
- Policies and procedures, 1965 - 1972; F-26-1; 2 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of departmental constitution and goals.
  - Constitutions, 1969 - 1972; F-26-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - Goals, 1965 - 1969; F-26-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
- Correspondence, 1964 - 1980; F-26-2; 36 cm of textual records
  Series consists of correspondence received and sent by the Department Chair. It includes memoranda and reports.
  Access may be restricted in accordance with Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy legislation. Consult the unit list and the archivist for further information.
  - Memoranda, 1964 - 1979; F-26-2-1; 7 cm of textual records
    - Office of the President, 1967 - 1977; F-26-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Vice-President, Academic, 1972 - 1977; F-26-2-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Dean of Arts, 1973 - 1977; F-26-2-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Head, 1964 - 1965; F-26-2-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Head, 1966; F-26-2-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Head, 1967; F-26-2-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Head, 1968; F-26-2-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Head/Chairman, 1969 - 1974; F-26-2-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Chairman, 1975 - 1979; F-26-2-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
  - Subject Files, 1964 - 1980; F-26-2-2; 29 cm of textual records
    - Africa/Middle East Studies, 1971 - 1978; F-26-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
      Open
    - Budget, 1968 - 1980; F-26-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Canadian Studies, 1971 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Committee for Community Education in the Arts, 1977; F-26-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Continuing Studies, 1971 - 1975; F-26-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-1)
    - Continuing Studies, 1976 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Curriculum, 1974 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Department Development, 1964 - 1970; F-26-2-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Directed Independent Studies Courses, 1975 - 1978; F-26-2-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Enrolment Statistics, 1964 - 1975; F-26-2-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Faculty Association, 1976 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Faculty of Science, 1975 - 1976; F-26-2-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Graduate Studies, 1975 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Guest Lecturers, 1970 - 1972; F-26-2-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Guest Lecturers, 1973; F-26-2-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Guest Lecturers, 1974; F-26-2-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Guest Lecturers, 1975 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - Guest Lecturers, 1979; F-26-2-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 26-2)
    - History Student Union, 1969 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Interdisciplinary Studies, 1970 - 1978; F-26-2-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Latin American Studies, 1971 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Library, 1970 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Personnel, 1971 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Programs of Excellence, 1977 - 1980; F-26-2-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Public History, 1978 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Secondary School Liaison, 1965 - 1978; F-26-2-2-0-26 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Space Allocation, 1975 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-27 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Student Discipline, 1976 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-28 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Student Discipline, 1977 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-29 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
      Restricted in whole
    - Student Employment Program, 1976 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-30 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Student Services, 1978 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-31 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Student Society, 1979; F-26-2-2-0-33 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Teaching Assistants, 1968 - 1973; F-26-2-2-0-34 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Teaching Assistants, 1974 - 1979; F-26-2-2-0-35 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
    - Universities and Colleges, 1974 - 1977; F-26-2-2-0-36 (Archival box - standard 26-3)
- Faculty members, 1965 - 1982; F-26-3; 50 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files related to the appointment, salary, and tenure of faculty members, as well as research grants. It includes correspondence, curricula vitae, memoranda and reports.
  - Appointments, 1965 - 1980; F-26-3-1; 21 cm of textual records
    - Appointments - A, 1965 - 1978; F-26-3-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - A, 1975 - 1976; F-26-3-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - B, 1976 - 1977; F-26-3-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - B, 1966 - 1972; F-26-3-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - B, 1972 - 1973; F-26-3-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - B, 1978 - 1979; F-26-3-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - E, 1965 - 1967; F-26-3-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - G, 1979 - 1980; F-26-3-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - G, 1973 - 1974; F-26-3-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - H, 1976 - 1979; F-26-3-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - H, 1965 - 1972; F-26-3-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - K, 1968 - 1974; F-26-3-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - L, 1978 - 1980; F-26-3-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - L, 1975 - 1977; F-26-3-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - L, 1975 - 1977; F-26-3-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - M, 1973 - 1974; F-26-3-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - M, 1971 - 1978; F-26-3-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - M, 1974 - 1976; F-26-3-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - M, 1973 - 1977; F-26-3-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - P, 1975 - 1976; F-26-3-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
    - Appointments - P, 1973 - 1974; F-26-3-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Appointments - S, 1979; F-26-3-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Appointments - S, 1972 - 1975; F-26-3-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Appointments - S, 1972 - 1979; F-26-3-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Appointments - V, 1970 - 1973; F-26-3-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Appointments - W, 1973 - 1974; F-26-3-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Appointments - W, 1975 - 1978; F-26-3-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - History of Science Appointments, 1970 - 1976; F-26-3-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Western Canadian History Appointment, 1979; F-26-3-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Women's Studies/History Appointment, 1975 - 1980; F-26-3-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
  - Tenured faculty, 1965 - 1982; F-26-3-2; 8 cm of textual records
    - Tenured faculty - B, 1965 - 1976; F-26-3-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Tenured faculty - B, 1977 - 1980; F-26-3-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Tenured faculty - C, 1965 - 1971; F-26-3-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Tenured faculty - C, 1972 - 1979; F-26-3-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-5)
    - Tenured faculty - K, 1974 - 1982; F-26-3-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Tenured faculty - M, 1967 - 1979; F-26-3-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Tenured faculty - W, 1974 - 1976; F-26-3-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
  - Salary review, 1966 - 1979; F-26-3-3; 15 cm of textual records
    - Salary Review, 1966 - 1968; F-26-3-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Salary Review, 1969; F-26-3-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Salary Review, 1970; F-26-3-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Salary Review, 1971; F-26-3-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Salary Review, 1972; F-26-3-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Salary Review, 1973; F-26-3-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-6)
    - Salary Review, 1973; F-26-3-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Salary Review, 1974; F-26-3-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Salary Review, 1974; F-26-3-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Salary Review, 1975 - 1977; F-26-3-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Salary Review, 1978 - 1979; F-26-3-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
  - Research grants, 1977 - 1980; F-26-3-4; 3 cm of textual records
    - President's Research Grants, 1978 - 1979; F-26-3-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council, 1977 - 1980; F-26-3-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
  - Correspondence, 1968 - 1975; F-26-3-5; 4 cm of textual records
    - Sabbatical leave, 1968 - 1972; F-26-3-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Sabbatical leave, 1973 - 1975; F-26-3-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
    - Faculty status reports, 1971; F-26-3-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-7)
  - Faculty Lists, F-26-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-4)
- Departmental committees, 1966 - 1980; F-26-4; 59 cm of textual records
  Series consists of the records of various departmental committees. It includes circulars, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and memoranda.
  - Appointments committee, 1968 - 1979; F-26-4-1; 6 cm of textual records
    - Appointments Committee, 1968 - 1971; F-26-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Appointments Committee, 1972; F-26-4-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Appointments Committee, 1973; F-26-4-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Appointments Committee, 1973; F-26-4-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Appointments Committee, 1974 - 1979; F-26-4-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
  - Chairman's Search Committee, 1970 - 1974; F-26-4-2; 1 cm of textual records
    - Chairman's Search Committee, 1970 - 1974; F-26-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
  - Departmental meetings, 1966 - 1973; F-26-4-3; 13 cm of textual records
    - Department Meetings, 1966; F-26-4-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Department Meetings, 1967; F-26-4-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Department Meetings, 1968; F-26-4-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
    - Agenda and Minutes, 1969; F-26-4-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Papers 1-71, 1969; F-26-4-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Agenda and Minutes, 1970; F-26-4-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Papers 72-125, 1970; F-26-4-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Agenda and Minutes, 1971; F-26-4-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Papers 126-165, 1971; F-26-4-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Agenda, Minutes and Papers, 1972 - 1973; F-26-4-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
  - Goals and Implementation Committee, 1969 - 1970; F-26-4-4; 3 cm of textual records
    - Goals and Implementation Committee, 1969; F-26-4-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
    - Goals and Implementation Committee, 1970; F-26-4-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-9)
  - Graduate Studies Committee, 1967 - 1972; F-26-4-5; 5 cm of textual records
    - Graduate Studies Committee, 1967; F-26-4-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Graduate Studies Committee, 1968; F-26-4-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Graduate Studies Committee, 1969; F-26-4-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Graduate Studies Committee, 1970; F-26-4-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Graduate Studies Committee, 1971 - 1972; F-26-4-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
  - Library Committee, 1969 - 1971; F-26-4-6; 1 cm of textual records
    - Library Committee, 1969 - 1971; F-26-4-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
  - Nominating Committee, 1971; F-26-4-7; 1 cm of textual records
    - Nominating Committee, 1971; F-26-4-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
  - Student-Faculty Liaison Committee, 1968 - 1970; F-26-4-8; 2 cm of textual records
    - Student-Faculty Liaison Committee, 1968; F-26-4-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Student-Faculty Liaison Committee, 1969 - 1970; F-26-4-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
  - Tenure Committee, 1968 - 1979; F-26-4-9; 13 cm of textual records
    - Tenure Committee, 1968 - 1969; F-26-4-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Tenure Committee, 1970; F-26-4-9-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Tenure Committee, 1971 - 1972; F-26-4-9-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Tenure Committee, 1972; F-26-4-9-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-10)
    - Tenure Committee, 1972; F-26-4-9-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1972; F-26-4-9-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1973; F-26-4-9-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1974; F-26-4-9-0-7.1 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1974; F-26-4-9-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1974; F-26-4-9-0-9 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1975 - 1977; F-26-4-9-0-10 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Tenure Committee, 1978 - 1979; F-26-4-9-0-11 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
  - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1968 - 1980; F-26-4-10; 11 cm of textual records
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1968 - 1969; F-26-4-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1970 - 1971; F-26-4-10-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1972 - 1973; F-26-4-10-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-11)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1974 - 1975; F-26-4-10-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1976 - 1980; F-26-4-10-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee - Curriculum Revision, 1970 - 1971; F-26-4-10-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee - Curriculum Revision, 1974; F-26-4-10-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee - Curriculum Revision, 1974; F-26-4-10-0-8 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
  - Ad hoc committees, 1968 - 1972; F-26-4-11; 2 cm of textual records
    - Ad Hoc Committees, 1968 - 1972; F-26-4-11-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
  - Departmental committees, 1969 - 1971; F-26-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-8)
- Departmental reviews, 1970 - 1974; F-26-5; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of materials relating to an external review of the Department in 1974. It includes correspondence, memoranda, and reports.
  - Department Review Committee, 1970; F-26-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
  - External Review, 1974; F-26-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-12)
  - External Review, 1974; F-26-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - External Review, 1974; F-26-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - External Review - Reports, 1974; F-26-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
- Course outlines, 1975 - 1979; F-26-6; 3 cm of textual records
  Series consists of undergraduate and graduate course outlines.
  - History 146-226, 1975; F-26-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - History 293-484, 1975; F-26-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - Course offerings, Spring, 1979; F-26-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
- Publications, 1966 - 1993; F-26-7; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of departmental and external publications, including the Departmental Newsletter.
  - Department Publications, 1966 - 1981; F-26-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - Newsletter No. 1-53, 1981 - 1983; F-26-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - Newsletter No. 54-86, 1983 - 1989; F-26-7-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - Publications of Faculty, 1978 - 1980; F-26-7-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - Canadian Historical Review, 1967 - 1977; F-26-7-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - International History Review, 1975; F-26-7-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
  - Departmental Publications, 1993; F-26-7-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 26-13)
- Associations, 1968 - 1971; F-26-8; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to professional associations to which members of the Department belonged. It includes correspondence and memoranda.
  - B.C. History Faculty Liaison Committee, 1968 - 1970; F-26-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - Fraser Valley East Social Studies Association, 1971; F-26-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - Northwest Conference of History Students, 1969; F-26-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - Vancouver Secondary School Teachers Association, 1969; F-26-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
- Conferences, 1969 - 1994; F-26-9; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records related to conferences hosted by the Department or attended by faculty members. It includes booklets, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and reports.
  - History Articulation Meetings, 1975 - 1979; F-26-9-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - SFU / UVic Symposium, 1975 - 1978; F-26-9-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - Papers - Fifth Annual Northwest History Conference [file missing], 1969; F-26-9-0-0-3
  - UVic Conference - BC and Beyond: Gender Histories, 1994; F-26-9-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - Vancouver Conference on Exploration and Discovery, vol. 1, 1992; F-26-9-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 26-14)
  - Vancouver Conference on Exploration and Discovery, vol. 2, 1992; F-26-9-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 26-14)